<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><root><header><name>uneclac cepalstat api</name><version>1.9.13</version><success>True</success><machine>02</machine><context>public</context><code>200</code><message></message><timestamp>1762875990</timestamp></header><body><metadata><indicator_id>4788</indicator_id><indicator_name>Total population, by sex</indicator_name><theme>Demographics (CELADE)</theme><area>Population</area><note></note><unit>Thousands of persons, at mid-year</unit><data_features>Annual estimations and projections of population for the period 1950-2100</data_features><definition>Number of inhabitants that actually live within the borders of the country, territory or given area.</definition><calculation_methodology>The population estimates and projections are produced by Population Division of ECLAC (CELADE) and Population Division of United Nations. This revision cover a 150-year time horizon, which can be subdivided into past estimates (1950-2015) and future projections (2015-2100). The past estimates were produced by starting with a base population by age and sex for 1 July 1950 and advancing the population through successive 5-year time intervals using the cohort-component method, based on age-specific estimates of the components of population change (fertility, mortality, and international migration). Population counts by age and sex from periodic censuses were used as benchmarks. The relevant estimates of demographic components for 1950-2015 were taken directly from national statistical sources, or were estimated by staff of the Population Division when only partial or poor-quality data were available. Necessary adjustments were made for deficiencies in age reporting, under-enumeration, or underreporting of vital events.

The year 2015, separating the past estimates from the projections, is called the base year of the projections. The projection period of this revision covers 85 years and ends in 2100. Population projections prepared by the United Nations Population Division and CELADE historically have been produced for a number of different variants to highlight, for instance, the effect of changes in the assumptions about the future trajectories of fertility on the future size and structure of the population.

More recently a probabilistic approach was added to the projection of certain components, such as total fertility and life expectancy at birth by sex.</calculation_methodology><comments>The figures for total population, as well as other demographic indicators corresponding to twenty Latin American countries are elaborated by CELADE - Population Division of ECLAC. The figures for the countries and territories of the Caribbean are elaborated by United Nations Population Division. Both figures are published in the World Population Prospects, which is released every two or three years for a total of 237 countries or areas that sum up the world’s population.
It should be stressed that making projections to 2100 is subject to a high degree of uncertainty, especially at the country level. In that regard, users are invited to focus not only on the outcomes of the medium variant, which for each country corresponds to the mean of several thousand projected trajectories of each demographic component, but also on the associated prediction intervals, which provide an assessment of the uncertainty inherent in such projections and are available at: https://population.un.org/wpp/.
With respect to the projection period, statistical techniques based mostly on the demographic transition theory were used to determine the paths that fertility, mortality and international migration are expected to follow in the future. In some cases, deviations from these guidelines or default mean probabilistic trajectories were required. This was mainly the case for the projection of net international migration and life expectancy at birth for selected countries and for some countries where the prevalence of HIV/AIDS was still relatively high in recent years. The Methodology of the United Nations population estimates and projections is available at: https://population.un.org/wpp/Publications/ .
</comments><decimals>1</decimals><last_update>Dec 12 2024 12:21PM</last_update></metadata></body><footer><records>1</records><elapsed_time>0.02489</elapsed_time><ip>190.49.25.195</ip><query>http://api-cepalstat.cepal.org/cepalstat/api/v1/indicator/4788/metadata?lang=en&amp;format=xml</query></footer></root>